<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Articles of enquiry given by [his Right Reverend Father in God James Lord Bishop of Wort.] and delivered to the church- wardens, and side-men, to be considered and answered in his visitation, holden in the year of our Lord God.</title>
            <author>Church of England. Diocese of Worcester. Bishop (1675-1683 : Fleetwood)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1680</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 17 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B08752</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C4009AC</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R175783</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">62369114</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 62369114</idno>
            <idno type="VID">187842</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B08752)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 187842)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2846:26)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Articles of enquiry given by [his Right Reverend Father in God James Lord Bishop of Wort.] and delivered to the church- wardens, and side-men, to be considered and answered in his visitation, holden in the year of our Lord God.</title>
                  <author>Church of England. Diocese of Worcester. Bishop (1675-1683 : Fleetwood)</author>
                  <author>Fleetwood, James, 1603-1683.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[12] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1680]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"His Right Reverend Father in God James Lord Bishop of Wort" written on t.p. in manuscript form.</note>
                  <note>Date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Harvard University. Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Church of England --  Pastoral letters and charges --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Visitations, Ecclesiastical --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="modern_bookplate">
            <pb facs="tcp:187842:1"/>
            <p>Harvard College Library</p>
            <figure>
               <head>VE<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>RI<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>TAS</head>
               <figDesc>Harvard seal</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>FROM THE BEQUEST OF JOHN HARVEY TREAT OF LAWRENCE, MASS. CLASS OF 1862</p>
         </div>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:187842:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:187842:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:187842:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>ARTICLES OF ENQUIRY Given by <add>
                  <seg rend="onBlank">the Right Rev<expan>
                        <am>
                           <g ref="char:aber"/>
                        </am>
                        <ex>er</ex>
                     </expan>end Father (Fleetwodd in God famos Lord Biſhop of <choice>
                        <abbr>Wort</abbr>
                        <expan>Worcester</expan>
                     </choice>.</seg>
               </add> and delivered to the Church-Wardens, and Side-men, to be conſidered and anſwered in his Viſitation, holden in the Year of our Lord God, <add>
                  <seg rend="onBlank">16<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </seg>
               </add>
            </p>
            <figure>
               <head>C R</head>
               <q xml:lang="frm">DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
               <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
               <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed.</p>
            <p>
               <add>ſee a different Copy of A<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                     <desc>…</desc>
                  </gap>y uſed by him at his visitation in 1676.</add>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="oath_to_be_administered_to_churchwardens_and_sidemen">
            <pb facs="tcp:187842:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>The Oath to be Miniſtred to the Church-Wardens and Side-men.</head>
            <p>YOU ſhall ſwear truly and faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully to execute the Office of Church-warden within your Pariſh for the Year enſuing accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the beſt of your Skill and Knowledg; and alſo preſent ſuch things and perſons as to your Knowledg are Preſentable by the Laws Ecceſiaſtical of this Realm. So help you God.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="articles_of_inquiry">
            <pb facs="tcp:187842:3"/>
            <div type="part">
               <head>ARTICLES OF ENQUIRY About the <hi>CH<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>RCHES</hi> and <hi>CHAPPELS:</hi> And all things thereto pertaining.</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>S your Pariſh Church or Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel kept in good and ſufficient Repair? Are the Roofs, Walls, Pavements, and Windows well Repaired? And is the Church decently kept, as befitteth the Houſe of God? Is your Church-Yard ſufficiently fenced and maintained with Walls, Rails, or Pales, as hath béen accuſtomed? Or by whoſe fault are they decayed? Hath any thing belonging to your Church been aliened, em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bezelled, or ſold?</p>
               <p n="2">2. Is there a Font of Stone for the Admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtration of Baptiſm, in the uſual place ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed for it? And doth your Miniſter pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lickly Baptize in the ſame Font only? Is there a convenient Table, for the uſe of the Lords Supper? Is there a Carpet of Silk, or decent
<pb facs="tcp:187842:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>Stuff to lay upon the Table in time of Divine Service; and a fair Linen Cloth to lay upon the ſame in the time of the Communion, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the eighty ſecond Canon: Have you a Communion Cup, with a Paten for the Bread: and is the Wine brought to the Communion Table in a clear ſtanding Pot or Flagon of Pewter, or of purer Metal?</p>
               <p n="3">3. Have you a Reading Desk and Pulpit con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veniently ſet up, and placed, for the uſe of pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Prayer, and Sermons?</p>
               <p n="4">4. Is there in your Church or Chappel the Common Prayer Book, of the largeſt Volume, according to the Act of Vniformity, 1662. The Bible in Folio, of the laſt Tranſlation; the Book of Homilies; [the Book of Canons, and Conſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutions Eccleſiaſtical, made in the Synod, 1603.] And a Table of Degrees, wherein Marriage is prohibited, publickly ſet up in your Church? And is there a decent Surplice for the Miniſter to wear at all times of his publick Miniſtration in the Church?</p>
               <p n="5">5. Have you a Regiſter Book in Parchment, wherein to Regiſter the Chriſtenings, Marriages, and Burials in your Pariſh? Is there a Book; wherein to write down the Church-Wardens Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compts, and a ſtrong Cheſt, with Locks and Keys, wherein to preſerve your Church Furniture; and alſo for the Pariſhioners to put in their Alms for the relief of the Poor?</p>
               <p n="6">6. Is the Houſe and Out-houſes of your Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter in good and ſufficient Repair? Doth he pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve the Gardens, Orchards, and Glebe belong<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to him, without embezelling, changing, or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny way damnifying the ſame?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:187842:4"/>
               <head>Inquiries about the Clergy.</head>
               <p n="1">1. IS your Parſon or Vicar Ordained Prieſt, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Order of the Church of <hi>England?</hi> Or doth your Miniſter, or his Curate not being ſo Ordained Prieſt, conſecrate the Holy Sacra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the Lords Supper?</p>
               <p n="2">2. Is your Miniſter legally Inſtituted, and Inducted into his Benefice? Did he within two Months after his Induction, publickly in the Church upon ſome Sunday or Holy-day, read the thirty nine Articles of the Church of <hi>England,</hi> and declare his aſſent thereunto? And alſo on ſome Lords-day read both Morning and Evening Prayer, and after his reading publickly declare his unfeigned Aſſent and Conſent to the uſe of the things contained in the Book of Common-Prayer? And within three Months after his In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duction, on ſome Lords-day in your Pariſh Church read a Certificate under the Hand and Seal of the Arch-Biſhop, or Biſhop of the Dioceſs, of his Subſcription to the Declaration required in the Act of Vniformity?</p>
               <p n="3">3. Doth your Miniſter read the full Service, according to the direction of the Common-Prayer Book on Sundays, and Holy-days, at Morning and Evening Prayer; and in miniſtring the Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>craments, ſolemnizing Matrimony, burying the Dead, and Churching of Women, uſe all the Rites and the whole Forms of Prayers, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording as they are preſcribed in the Common Prayer Book without omiſſion, alteration, or ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition? Or doth he negligently, or in contempt of the Order of the Church, omit or add to the ſame?</p>
               <pb facs="tcp:187842:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p n="4">4. Doth he uſually read the Book of Cannos once every Year, and wear a Surplice in the time of his Miniſtration?</p>
               <p n="5">5. Doth he Preach a Sermon on every Sun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day, or procure a Sermon then to be preached? Or elſe ſometime read one of the Homilies which the Church hath appointed? And doth he di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligently inſtruct the Youth of your Pariſh in the Church Catechiſm? And doth he endeavour to prepare them to be Confirmed by the Biſhop?</p>
               <p n="6">6. Is your Miniſter conſtantly reſident upon his Benefice? Or how long hath he been ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent? And in caſe he be licenſed to be abſent, whether doth he cauſe his Cure to be ſupplied by a ſufficient and licenſed Preacher? And is your Curate conformable to the Eccleſiaſtical Laws?</p>
               <p n="7">7. Doth your Miniſter or Curate read the Service appointed for the Fifth of <hi>November,</hi> the Thirtieth of <hi>January,</hi> and the Twenty ninth of <hi>May?</hi> And doth he give notice upon the Sunday of the Holy-days, and Faſting-days, which will be the Week following, and obſerve the yearly peram<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bulation in Rogation Week?</p>
               <p n="8">8. Doth your Miniſter or Curate, celebrate the Lords Supper in the Church ſo often, that every Pariſhioner may receive the ſame at leaſt thrice in the year? Doth he give warning of it, and read the Exhortation the Sunday before, that thereby the Pariſhioners may be ſtirr'd up to the worthy Receiving thereof? Doth he deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver ſeverally the Bread and Wine to every Communicant kneeling? Doth he admit them
<pb facs="tcp:187842:5"/>to the Communion, which be openly known to live in ſin notorious, without repentance, or to have maliciouſly and openly contended with their Neighbours, before they be reconciled? And if he hath repelled any perſon from the Communion, doth he give account to the Ordinary within four<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>téen days after?</p>
               <p n="9">9. Doth he Baptiſe ſuch Infants of his Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh, according to the Order of the Common Pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, as upon warning given before, are brought upon Sundays or Holy-days to the Church? And upon lawful ſummons doth he Baptize Infants at home, in caſe of danger and neceſſity? Or through his fault doth the Infant die unbapti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zed?</p>
               <p n="10">10. Doth he neglect to viſit the Sick at their Houſes when he is required? Doth he pray with them, and exhort them to Faith and Repentance; forgiveneſs of Injuries, and liberality to the Poor, and comfort them in their diſtreſs? And doth he give them that profeſs ſorrow for their ſins, the Holy Communion if they deſire it?</p>
               <p n="11">11. Doth he marry any within the Degrées prohibited? Or without Licence, or Banes pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhed thrée ſeveral Sundays, or Holy-days, in the Pariſhes where the Parties dwell? Doth he Marry in any other place than in the Church? Or not betwixt the lawful Hours of eight and twelve? And doth he, if the Banes have béen thrice asked, Marry any under the age of twenty one years, without their Parents or Guardians conſent?</p>
               <p n="12">12. Hath he taken upon him to appoint any publick or private Faſts, Propheſyings, or Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erciſes, not appointed by Authority, without Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cence
<pb facs="tcp:187842:6"/>from the Biſhop under his Hand and Seal firſt obtained: Or doth he, or any other perſon, hold any Conventicles, or Méetings in private Houſes, or elſewhere within your Pariſh, for people of ſeveral Families to reſort unto, under pretence of Preaching, or Praying?</p>
               <p n="13">13. Doth your Miniſter write and record in your Regiſter Book, the Names of all perſons Chriſtned, Married, and Buried within your Pariſh; with the day and year of ſuch Chriſtning, Marringe, and Burial? And doth he with the Church-Wardens, take care duly to ſend in a Tranſcript of the Regiſter every year to be kept in the Biſhops Regiſtry?</p>
               <p n="14">14. Is your Parſon, Vicar, Curate, or Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cturer a man of a ſober, unblameable, and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>emplary life: and ſpares not to preſent him or them that are not every way examples of godli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs? If you have a Curate, is he allowed by the Biſhop under his Hand and Seal: If you have a Lecturer, is he licenſed by the Biſhop ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Act of Vniformity? And doth he read the full Divine Service of Common-Prayer once a month at the leaſt? And doth your Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, Vicar, Curate, and Lecturer, (to your beſt underſtanding) preach ſound Doctrine, ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Edification of the people, in know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledg and faith of Ieſus Chriſt, and obedience to Gods Command? Or doth be Preach any hereti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal, ſeditious, or ſchiſmatical Doctrine, derogating from the Glory of God, and prejudicial to a pious life, or tending to the diſturbance of the publick peace and unity of Church or State? If there be any ſuch, preſent them.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:187842:6"/>
               <head>Inquiries concerning the Pariſhioners.</head>
               <p n="1">1. IF there be any Perſons that have offended by Fornication, Adultery, Inceſt, Drun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kenneſs, or by common Swearing, Ribaldry, fil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thy Speaking, or any other uncleanneſs, and wickedneſs of life, Sorcerers, or reſorters to Sorcerers, you ſhall preſent all and every ſuch Offenders.</p>
               <p n="2">2. If there be any known to be hinderers of the Word of God to be read and ſincerely Preached, or of the Exeution of the Eccleſiaſtical Canons in force, any Fautors of any Vſurped and Forein Power-taken away by the Laws of this Realm, any Defenders of Popiſh Doctrine, they are to be preſented.</p>
               <p n="3">3. Are there any Diſturbers of Divine Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice or Sermon, by walking, talking, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe? Are there any that have ſtricken and quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>relled with any perſon in your Church or Church-Yard? Do you Pariſhioners, in time of Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vine Service and Sermon, behave themſelves reverently, Men and Youth uncovering their Heads? do all kneel, ſtand up, make Anſwers in time of Divine Service, as is appointed in the Rubricks of the Common Prayer Book? Or are they publick Depravers of the Common Prayer, and the Orders and Rites of the Church of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land?</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="4">4. Do all your Pariſhioners reſort diligently to Service and Sermons in the Church on Sun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>days? and other days appointed to be kept or Holy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>days? Do any commonly come but to ſome part, or near, or at the latter end of Divine Service, or to the Sermon only? Do they continue tip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling
<pb facs="tcp:187842:7"/>and drinking during the Service and Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon, prophanely neglecting, or deſpiſing the Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties of Religion? Or do any ſeparate from the publick Worſhip of God in their Pariſh Church, and frequent unlawful Conventicles?</p>
               <p n="5">5. Do any occupy themſelves in their ordinary labour, or permit their Servants ſo to do? do they keep open their Shops, and ſell Wares on Sundays, or otherwiſe prophane the ſaid dayes, contrary to the Orders of the Church of <hi>England?</hi> Or do any Victuallers, Inn-keepers, Ale-houſe-keepers, or others permit any to lie tipling in their Houſes on thoſe days?</p>
               <p n="6">6. Are there any in your Pariſh being above ſixteen years of Age, and well inſtructed in Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion, who do not receive the Sacrament of the Lords Supper at leaſt thrée times in the Year, of which <hi>Eaſter</hi> or thereabouts to be one? Or is there any who refuſe it Knéeling, and from the Hand of their own Miniſter, repairing for it to other Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes, and Miniſters abroad?</p>
               <p n="7">7. Are there any in your Pariſh who keep their Children unbaptized? Are there any who cauſe them to be Baptized privately, by any whom your Miniſter doth not allow, or after any other Form and Manner than is preſcribed by the L<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turgy? Or any that procure themſelves to be Married privately, or after any other manner than the Church preſcribes? Or any who being admoniſhed refuſe to ſend their Children and Servants to be Catechiſed? or any who refuſe to be Catechiſed?</p>
               <p n="8">8. Are there any Women in your Pariſh, who after their delivery from Child-birth, have re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſed to make publick Thankſgiving to God,
<pb facs="tcp:187842:7"/>according as is preſcribed in the Common Prayer Book?</p>
               <p n="9">9. Do your Pariſhioners bring their Dead to be buried according to the Order of the Church? Or have any been carried away to ſome other place to be buried, without the Miniſters leave?</p>
               <p n="10">10. Are there any who refuſe to pay their <hi>Ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter</hi> Offerings, and Eccleſiaſtical Duties accu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomed then to be paid? Or that refuſe to pay the Rates aſſeſſed on them for the repair of Your Church or Chappel, or for the providing of Books, Vtenſils, or neceſſary Ornaments, or defraying ſuch Charges as are by Law or Cuſtom requi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red?</p>
               <p n="11">11. Are there any in Your Pariſh Married within the Degrées prohibited by the Laws of God? Or any that being lawfully Married and not ſeparated by courſe of Law, do not co-habit to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether? And do any with-hold the Stock of the Church, or any Goods, or Things given to Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritable Vſes?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Inquiries concerning Church Officers, and other Perſons.</head>
               <p n="1">1. DOth any kéep a publick or private School in Your Pariſh who is not licenſed by the Biſhop of the Dioceſs? And doth he breed his Scholars religiouſly, and teach them the Church Catechiſm?</p>
               <p n="2">2. Have You a Pariſh Clerk of twenty Years of Age at the leaſt? Is he of honeſt life and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſation? Is he choſen by Your Miniſter: and ſufficient for Reading and Singing? Is he allowed by the Ordinary? Are his and the Sextons Wages paid without fraud, according
<pb facs="tcp:187842:8" rendition="simple:additions"/>to the Cuſtom of your Pariſh? or who with-holds them?</p>
               <p n="3">3. Have you any Phyſician, Chirurgion, or Midwife that practiſe without Licence?</p>
               <p n="4">4. Are the Church-Wardens of your Pariſh Yearly choſen, according to the Canon or Cuſtom of the Pariſh? Have the late Church-Wardens given up a juſt Account, delivering up to the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhioners the Money remaining in their hands, and other things of right belonging to your Church or Chappel? Are the Alms of the Church faithful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly diſtributed to the uſe of the Poor? If any be faulty, preſent them.</p>
               <p n="5">5. If any Stranger come to preach in Your Church on any occaſion, you muſt demand to ſee his Licence to Preach, and if he have none, you muſt inhibit him from Preaching; and if he has a Licence, cauſe him to ſubſcribe his Name in Your Book, with the Name of the Biſhop who li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſed him.</p>
               <p n="6">6. Is there provided againſt every Communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on a ſufficient quantity of fine white Bread, and wholeſome Wine, according to the number of the Communicants, by the Advice of your Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter? And is the Wine brought to the Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion Table in a ſwéet ſtanding Pot or Flaggon?</p>
               <p n="7">7. Do you know, or have you heard that the Church-Wardens, or Side-men, which were your immediate Predeceſſors, have refuſed or neglected to do the duty of their Office during their time; and wherein are they faulty?</p>
               <p n="8">8. Do any perſons trouble you for preſenting any that offend in the Premiſes, and who they are?</p>
               <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               <pb facs="tcp:187842:8"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:187842:9"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:187842:9"/>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
